CAMILA APARICIO

647-975-7248 camilaaparicio.com camilaaparicioo@hotmail.com



PROFILE

A front-end developer with a passion for creating visually appealing, accessible, and responsive user interfaces that enhance the user experience. My past experiences have cultivated my strong communication and problem-solving skills. I have a constant desire and eagerness to keep learning and broadening my knowledge in web development.

Languages: English & Spanish

SKILLS

HTML5

CSS3 · SCSS

JavaScript · REST APIs

ReactJS

Responsive Design · Browser Testing

Content Management Systems

Git / GitHub · Command Line

Web Accessibility - WCAG 2.0 & AODA

Figma · Wireframes & Mockups

PROJECTS

CrossPlay @ Canadian Red Cross www.redcross.ca/crossplay/

Developed using Kentico CMS, this custom site is for gamers to support the CRC fundraising. Worked on the design for mobile and desktop views. Collaborated with design and full-stack developer to build this site.

Holiday Campaign @ Canadian Red Cross www.redcross.ca/donate22

Worked closely with the design team and developers to bring the 2022 holiday campaign website to life, integrating interactive elements and ensuring that all content was properly formatted and displayed.

Meme in a Giffy @ Juno College Github Repo / Live Site

A group-programmed React application that allows users to generate their own memes by inputting text and saving their favourite results by using Firebase.

EXPERIENCE

UI Web Developer @ Canadian Red Cross March 2022 - Present | Maternity Leave Contract

- Develop and maintain redcross.ca, crioxrouge.ca, campaign microsites, and other digital platforms with HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript.
- Works in an Agile environment using Jira project management.
- Collaborate closely with the Design and Marketing teams creating mock-ups for updated, modern, accessible UI web parts and pages.
- Experience with accessibility audit reports using tools to ensure AODA standards and WCAG 2.0 guidelines for redcross.ca, and for other Red Cross teams were being met.

Pension Technician @ LifeWorks 2019 - 2022

- Calculated and issued benefit payments in accordance with plan rules and legislation.
- Answered queries from clients, plan members and trustees, providing relevant information and appropriate follow-up.

EDUCATION

Juno College of Technology

- · Web Development Immersive Bootcamp 2021
- · Accelerated JavaScript 2021
- UX Design 2023

University of Guelph-Humber Honours Bachelor of Applied Science in Social Work 2012-2016